We've created a list using the square brackets
我们已经使用方括号建立了列表
that contains 5 strings.
包含5个字符串
Each one is a 1-letter string spelling out the word "Hello."
每一个字符串都包含一个字符 拼出 Hello 一词
And we've stored that in the variable p.
将其存储在变量 p 中
We could do the same thing we did with strings.
我们可以进行之前的操作
We could reassign p to a new value.
赋予 p 一个新值
And if we did that, that would create a new list
这样做就建立了新的列表
containing the letters Y-E-L-L-O
包含 Yello 的字样
and assign that to the variable p.
并将其储存在 p 中
What we're going to do instead is mutate the list that we already created,
现在呢 我们将对这个列表进行变化
and we can do that by modifying the value of its elements.
通过改变其元素的值来变
Here we have an assignment where on the left side of the assignment
这里我们有一个赋值语句
we have p[0].
左侧是 p[0]
This means select from the list that p refers to.
意思是从 p 当中选择元素
Find position 0.
找到位置0
Instead of getting the value at that position, though,
然而 这一步并不获得该位置的值
since it's on the left side of an assignment now,
因为我们把它写在赋值语句的左边
we're going to replace that value with what's on the right side of the assignment,
将用赋值语句右边的值来替换该位置的值
in this case, the string containing the single letter y.
现在 我们用含有字母 y 的字符串来进行替换
Let's see what that looks like.
来看一下结果
When we created the list initially,
最初的列表
we had a list like this, and I'm going to draw the list showing boxes.
是这样的 我把各元素框起来
This is a list.
这是一个列表
Each box is 1 element of the list,
每一个框框都是其中一个元素
and after the initial assignment, the value p refers to is this list.
最初的赋值语句得到的变量 p 指代的是这个列表
Now when we do the assignment where p[0] is on the left side,
现在 p[0] 在左侧
well, p[0] will find this position.
p[0] 会找到这个位置
The assignment will replace what's there.
本语句将改变这个位置的值
So, replace the H with the Y.
所以 Y 替代了 H
Note that we did not create a new list.
注意 我们并未创立新列表
P still refers to the same list. We didn't have to change the arrow.
p 仍然指代原来的列表 箭头也不用做任何改动
But we've changed the value of that list.
但我们改变了这个列表的值
Let's try this in the Python interpreter.
在 Python 解释器里试一下
I've created a list with the elements being 5 strings
最初的列表 元素是5个字符串
spelling out the word "Hello."
拼出 Hello 一词
And I can see that that's the value of p.
这也是 p 的值
Now I'm going to use the assignment expression
现在我将使用赋值表达式
to replace the value in the first element
替换第一个元素的值
and print p again.
重新打印 p
Now when we run, we see that for the first print
运行 第一次打印时
the value of p is Hello.
p 的值为 Hello
For the second print, the value of p is Yellow.
第二次打印时 p 的值是 Yello
We can change other values the same way,
同样 我们也可以改变其他元素的值
so now we've changed the value in position 4
现在我们将位置4元素的值
to an exclamation point, and we can see
改成惊叹号
the third line printed out.
第三次打印
We have "Yell!"
结果是 Yell!